# JACOB ARMSTEAD

NETWORK ENGINEER



+1.559.307.7836



jacobarmstead@gmail.com
Seattle, Washington



linkedin.com/in/jacobarmstead

## in

#### CERTIFICATES

CySA+

MAY 2019 - Current

CCNA R&S

JUNE 2016 - Current

SECURITY + CE

APRIL 2013 - Current

MCSA WINDOWS 10 MARCH 2018 - Current

A+ JUNE 2016 - Current

#### EDUCATION

#### UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX

Graduate October 2019 Bachelors in Information Technology

#### GRANTHAM UNIVERSITY

Information Technology 2014-2016

#### FRESNO CITY COLLEGE

Computer Science 2011-2012

#### SKILLS

CISCO R&S

EIGRP, OSPF, BGP, RIP

**CLOUD CONCEPTS** 

WINDOWS SERVER

2012R2 / 2016R2

ACTIVE DIRECTORY / GROUP POLICY

NETWORK SECURITY CISCO FIREWALL / ACCESS LIST

323

HYPER-V / VSphere

VMWARE ESXi 6

.

LINUX CLI

**SOLARWINDS** 

NETWORK DESIGN

**POWERSHELL** 

SHELL SCRIPTING

OFFICE 365

VPN

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

- Clearance level: SECRET
- I am a dedicated network professional with 7 years of hands on experience
  working in live tactical and enterprise network environments. My primary roles
  include configuring and troubleshooting layer 1, 2, and 3 networks while increasing
  network optimization and improving security. I have a lifelong eagerness to learn
  and grow in technical abilities of all areas in information technology.

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Network Systems Administrator

1st Special Forces Group Signal Detachment • Oct 2018 – Current • JBLM, Washington

- Responsible for administering WAN, LAN networks on 3 domain classifications
- Incorporated dynamic routing protocols (EIGRP) to streamline data communication through load balancing techniques through the course of 3 years and 15 different military training exercises
- Applied network security measures using access list, port security, and firewall methods
- Configured and installed multiple Windows Servers 2012 R2 in order to provide network services to include DHCP, Group Policy, Active Directory, DNS, WDS, Remote Access Management, and File and Storage Services.

### Cyber Security Technician

1<sup>st</sup> Special Forces Group Technical Surveillance Detachment • Sep 2017 – Oct 2018 • JBLM, Washington

- Implemented various methods to crack WEP, WAP, & WPA2 networks through the use of Kali Lunix & Aircrack-NG
- Metasploit exploitation's on Windows 7 & Windows 10
- Applied Network / system hardening
- Conducted information gathering that positively effected mission control through the use of applications such as NMAP and Wireshark
- Created custom Raspberry Pi configurations for surveillance and information gathering

#### Network / Server Technician

1st Special Forces Group Signal Detachment • Aug 2016 – Sep 2017 • JBLM, Washington

- Set up multiple complex networking sites by configuring cisco switches / routers and implementing Windows Server 2012 R2 Services to easily manage each site
- Used advanced trouble shooting methods to resolve network latencies and improve network flow on overseas networks that were used to protect U.S Soldiers lives (maintaining a 99.999% uptime)

#### Helpdesk Technician

7<sup>th</sup> Special Forces Group • Feb 2013 – July 2016 • Eglin AFB, Florida

- Primarily troubleshot basic computing environment issues (completing over two thousand trouble tickets in a 2-year span.
- Administered Active Directory, Microsoft Exchange Server, Windows Server 2012R2, & Group Policy Objects
- Administered over 500+ user accounts